# **AKEEM BRISCO**

# **UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO**

briscoakeem@gmail.com

https://github.com/akeembrisco

\* www.linkedin.com/in/akeem-brisco-6b3b47128

# **SUMMARY**

As a motivated Software Developer with over 2 years of experience in the software industry, I possess strong problem-solving and leadership skills. With 2+ years as a Developer, I excel in Agile, REST API, and client-side & server-side development. I offer valuable skills in mobile-friendly app development and experience in both higher education and continuous integration environments.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# **Accedo** – Software Developer

September 2022 – April 2023

- Crafted responsive web apps with 32,000+ monthly active users, leveraging mobile traffic growth aligned with strategic collaboration across marketing and sales teams.
- Resolved critical bugs, enhancing user experience, and optimizing web applications.
- Developed and managed 20+ responsive web apps, driving increased user engagement.
- Engineered UWP app for Xbox One using C++, HTML/JavaScript, .NET, Visual Studio 2017, and latest Windows 10 SDK.

# Accedo – Web Developer

April 2021 – September 2022

- Led E-Commerce platform development, driving online sales and customer retention.
- Developed responsive web apps, aligning with marketing strategies to boost mobile traffic.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams of designers and developers to identify and solve complex technical problems, including project architecture, backlog refinement, and future planning.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Toronto**

- Honours Bachelor of Science (HBSc)
- Computer Science, Mathematics, Communication Culture Information & Technology

#### APPLICATIONS AND PROJECTS

**Sensical** – Software Developer

September 2021 – April 2023

Front-end developer at Sensical (<a href="https://www.sensical.tv">https://www.sensical.tv</a>), a free streaming service for kids, fostering social, emotional, and cognitive development. Contributed to the seamless integration of mobile-friendly features and optimized user interfaces to enhance overall user experience.

ReactJS, SCSS, MEAN, HTML, Python, CSS, Jira, Agile, Bitbucket, GitHub

#### **Dream Code** – Software Developer

January 2021 – September 2021

Dream Code is a full-stack web application for learning coding languages such as Python, C++, and Java. It caters to all age groups interested in learning these languages.

• NodeJS, HTML, CSS, jQuery, ReactJS, C++, GitHub, Python, Jira

## **SKILLS**

- Full-Stack Development: Agile, REST API, Client-Side & Server-Side Dev
- CMS: Drupal, squarespace, Shopify, WordPress
- Higher Education Experience
- Continuous Integration & Pipeline Environment
- Front-End: ReactJS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Typescript
- Back-End: NodeJS, Python, Java, PHP, C#
- Tools: Jira, GitHub, Bitbucket

**(**289)-600-9509